Changho Shin

cshin23@wisc.edu https://ch-shin.github.io 1210 W Dayton St, Madison, WI 53706

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research is focused on **foundation models**, including **large language models** and **multimodal foundation models**. Some of my work aims to efficiently help these models adopt new skills. This involves two prongs: (1) **approaches for obtaining and selecting fine-tuning data**, often by using a strategy called **weak supervision** and (2) **efficient adaptation**, including training-free approaches like **model editing**.

EDUCATION

University of Wisconsin-Madison

Sep. 2020 –

- Ph.D. Computer Science, M.S. Mathematics
- Advisor: Professor Frederic Sala

Seoul National University

Mar. 2015 - Feb. 2017

- M.S. Machine Learning
- Advisor: Professor Wonjong Rhee

Seoul National University

Mar. 2011 - Feb. 2015

- B.A. in Psychology, B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering
- Graduated with honors (Cum Laude)

HONORS & AWARDS

Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship Finalist	2024
Best Paper Award Honorable Mention (NeurIPS R0-FoMo Workshop)	2023
NeurIPS 2023 Scholar Award	2023
Winner in DataComp competition (Filtering Track, Small)	2023
CS Departmental Scholarship (University of Wisconsin-Madison)	2020

CONFERENCE PUBLICATIONS

- [C1] Changho Shin, Jitian Zhao, Sonia Cromp, Harit Vishwakarma, Frederic Sala, "OTTER: Improving Zero-Shot Classification via Optimal Transport", Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2024.
- [C2] Dyah Adila*, Changho Shin*, Linrong Cai, Frederic Sala, "Zero-Shot Robustification of Zero-Shot Models With Auxiliary Foundation Models", International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2024.
 Workshop version [W1]: Best Paper Award Honorable Mention, Oral Presentation at NeurIPS 2023 R0-FoMo Workshop.
- [C3] Changho Shin, Sonia Cromp, Dyah Adila, Frederic Sala, "Mitigating Source Bias for Fairer Weak Supervision", Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2023.
- [C4] Changho Shin, Winfred Li, Harit Vishwakarma, Nicholas Roberts, Frederic Sala, "Universalizing Weak Supervision", International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2022.
- [C5] Changho Shin, Sunghwan Joo, Jaeryun Yim, Hyoseop Lee, Taesup Moon, Wonjong Rhee, "Subtask Gated Networks for Non-Intrusive Load Monitoring", AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2019.

JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

- [J1] Changho Shin, Eunjung Lee, Jeongyun Han, Jaeryun Yim, Hyoseop Lee, Wonjong Rhee, "The ENERTALK Dataset, 15 Hz Electricity Consumption Data from 22 Houses in Korea", Nature Scientific Data, 2019 (Impact Factor = 5.929).
- [J2] **Changho Shin**, Seungeun Rho, Hyoseop Lee, Wonjong Rhee, "Data Requirements for Applying Machine Learning to Energy Disaggregation", *Energies*, May 2019 (Impact Factor = 2.707).

WORKSHOP PUBLICATIONS

- [W1] Changho Shin, John Cooper, Dyah Adila, Frederic Sala, "Weak-to-Strong Generalization Through the Data-Centric Lens", ICML 2024 DMLR Workshop, 2024.
- [W2] Dyah Adila, Changho Shin, Yijing Zhang, Frederic Sala, "Can Language Models Safeguard Themselves, Instantly and For Free?", ICML 2024 Next Generation of AI Safety Workshop, 2024.
- [W3] Dyah Adila*, Changho Shin*, Linrong Cai, Frederic Sala, "Foundation Models Can Robustify Themselves, For Free", NeurIPS 2023 R0-FoMo Workshop. Best Paper Award Honorable Mention, Oral Presentation.
- [W4] Changho Shin*, Joon Suk Huh*, Elina Choi, "Pool-Search-Demonstrate: Improving Data-wrangling LLMs via better in-context examples", NeurIPS 2023 Table Representation Learning (TRL) Workshop. Oral Presentation.
- [W5] **Changho Shin***, Tzu-heng Huang*, Sui Jiet Tay, Dyah Adila, Frederic Sala, "Multimodal Data Curation via Object Detection and Filter Ensembles", *ICCV* 2023 Datacomp Workshop (Rank #1 in DataComp competition filtering track (small)).
- [W6] Changho Shin, Alice Schoenauer-Sebag, "Can we get smarter than majority vote? Efficient use of individual rater's labels for content moderation", NeurIPS Efficient Natural Language and Speech Processing (ENLSP) Workshop, 2022.

PREPRENTS

[P1] Amanda Dsouza, Christopher Glaze, Changho Shin, Frederic Sala, "Understanding Long Context Models In Real-world Tasks: Benchmarks and Beyond", Under Review, 2024.

JOB EXPERIENCE

Snorkel AI, California, USA

Jun. 2024 – Aug. 2024

Research Intern

• Mentor: Christopher Glaze, Paroma Varma

Twitter, San Francisco, USA

Jun. 2022 – Aug. 2022

ML Engineer Intern

- Mentor: Alice Schoenauer Sebag Manager: Milind Ganjoo
- Improving toxicity classification via weak supervision [W4]

Encored Technologies, Seoul, Korea

Jan. 2018 - Jul. 2020

Data Scientist

- Advisor: Dr. Hyoseop Lee
- Non-intrusive load monitoring [C4, J1, J2], Energy forecasting

Korea Institute for Defense Analyses, Seoul, Korea

Jan. 2017 – Dec. 2017

Researcher

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

University of Wisconsin-Madison

• Teaching assistant for CS 839 (Foundation Models)

Fall 2023

• Teaching assistant for CS 300 (Programming II)

Fall 2022, Spring 2023

• Teaching assistant for CS 760 (Machine Learning)

Fall 2021, Spring 2022

 \bullet Teaching assistant for CS 320 (Data Programming II)

Spring 2021

• Teaching assistant for CS 220 (Data Programming I)

Fall 2020

GRADUATE COURSEWORK

- M2680.001300 Machine Learning for Information Studies @ SNU
- M2680.001400 Social Computing @ SNU
- 493.613 Mathematics for Intelligent Systems (Numerical Linear Algebra) @ SNU
- 493.701 Learning and Applications of Deep Neural Networks @ SNU
- M0000.005400 Convex Optimization @ SNU
- \bullet M0000.005400 Neural Networks @ SNU
- CS537 Introduction to Operating Systems @ UW
- CS639.004 Introduction to Computational Learning Theory @ UW

- CS726 Nonlinear Optimization 1
- CS744 Big Data Systems @ UW
- CS761 Mathematical Foundations of Machine Learning @ UW
- CS784 Foundations of Data Management @ UW
- CS787 Advanced Algorithms @ UW
- CS839 Probability and Learning in High Dimension @ UW
- CS880 Advanced Topics in Learning Theory @ UW
- Math521 Analysis I @ UW
- Math522 Analysis II @ UW
- Math551 Elementary Topology @ UW
- Math629 Introduction to Measure and Integration @ UW
- Math621 Analysis III (Analysis on Manifolds) @ UW
- Math721 A First Course in Real Analysis @ UW
- Math733 Theory of Probability I @ UW
- Math
734 Theory of Probability II @ UW Math
761 Differentiable Manifolds @ UW
- Math833 Modern Discrete Probability @ UW
- Math888 Randomized Linear Algebra @ UW
- Stat992 Optimal Transport and Applications to Machine Learning @ UW

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Machine Learning / Deep Learning / Data Science

PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, scikit-learn, NumPy, Pandas, SciPy

DBMS

MySQL, MongoDB, PySpark

Research & Development Tools

Visual Studio Code, Jupyter, PyCharm, Docker, GitHub, CircleCI, Shell, AWS

Programming Languages

Python, R, MATLAB, Java, Go, C, LATEX